## Edward ("Ted") Walther

http://warpedpuppv.com

https://github.com/warpedpuppy

ted@warpedpuppv.com

415.902.2952

Web Developer with extensive professional experience in the design, development and implementation of web sites, games, and applications. Notable project-related experience includes:

- Developed the front-end of a website with traffic of 20 million monthly pageviews.
- Coded in a boiler-room web game development environment, writing strong code quickly.
- Teach NodeJS and ReactJS to advanced web programming students through Thinkful.com.
- Coded and Maintained subscription based ecommerce site in VueJS and NuxtJS.
- Attend numerous continuing education seminars, most recently The Reactathon (for ReactJS) in SF.

### **Technical Skills:**

JavaScript (ReactJS, ReduxJS, VueJS, VueX, NuxtJS, NodeJS, ExpressJS, MongooseJS, Mongo), PHP, MySQL, AS3, HTML5, CSS, and more.

## **Professional Experience**

Thinkful.com, 2107-present

- One-on-one mentoring in web development fundamentals and full-stack programming.
- Teach JavaScript from fundamentals to advanced.
- Assisted students in app creation, both front-end and back-end.

### CleverTech. 2017-2018

- Coded and maintained an ecommerce site using VueJS, VueX and NuxtJS.
- Coordinated the site's use of Shopify, Stripe, Mailchimp and Wordpress apis.

## The Dodo, 2016-2017

- Wrote and maintained code for the entire front-end, and part of the back-end of the website.
- Worked directly with the Head of Product to create, edit and maintain site. Continually polished code to achieve optimized efficiency and operation.
- Collaborated with onshore and offshore development teams.
- Coded and implemented Google Analytics A/B experiments, which required creating alternate versions of the site and managed their application via lazy loaded JavaScript.
- Edited and maintained newsletter code with CampaignMonitor.

# WarpedPuppy LLC, 2013-2016

- Designed, developed and maintained front-ends and back-ends for websites and mobile applications.
- Maintained JavaScript playground site <a href="http://trvingsomething.com">http://trvingsomething.com</a>.

## Starfall Education, 2010-2013

- Programmed educational games for the website starfall.com and the site's paid section more.starfall.com.
- Was the only on-staff full-time programmer and had to code extremely complicated games quickly and efficiently.
- Collaborated with other designers to develop site assets and mobile applications.
- Created and implemented back-end strategies to support the web games.

### Education

Various Coding Certificates

Bachelor of Arts (B.A.)

AcademyX, San Francisco, CA

Two years of professional trade school focused in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, MySQL.

University of California, Hastings College of the Law Juris Doctor (J.D.)

Passed both the California and Connecticut bars. Awarded an HPILF grant.

Majored in History, Graduated with Honors.

University of California, Berkeley